A Guide to the Cary Reich papers FA1275
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Oral History Audio, circa 1980s (Bulk: 1982); 2
  - U-Z, 2.9
    - Vanden Heuvel, William, circa1980s; Sound, 91 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9772)
      Interview. Vanden Heuvel was special counsel to Governor Averell Harriman in 1958. In 1960, he ran for Congress as a Democrat against Republican incumbent John Lindsay in New York City's 17th Congressional District and lost. In the 1970s, vanden Heuvel served as chairman of the New York City Board of Corrections and, in 1973, challenged but lost to incumbent Frank Hogan in the Democratic Primary for Manhattan District Attorney.
    - Vandervoort, Jack, circa1980s; Sound, 177 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9773)
      Interview. Vandervoort was a campaign aide to Nelson Rockefeller. Vandervoort interview ends at 153 minutes, 50 seconds. Tape then contains phone call with Reich and a woman at the Lyndon Baines Johnson Library until 160 minutes, 3 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Harry Albright until end. Albright was an aide to Nelson Rockefeller, 1967-1975. During Rockefeller's governorship, Albright held various positions, including deputy secretary, executive secretary, and appointments officer. He was also state banking superintendent, 1972-1974. He then served has Rockefeller's special counsel when Rockefeller was Vice President.
    - von Hirsch, Andrew, circa1980s; Sound, 141 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9578)
      Interview. Von Hirsch was an aide to Senator Charles Goodell. Von Hirsch interview ends at 84 minutes, 30 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Sam Gould until 93 minutes, 21 seconds. Gould was chancellor of the State University of New York. Tape then contains partial interview with von Hirsch until 130 minutes, 25 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Hayward Plumadore until end. Plumadore was Franklin County Republican chairman.
    - Wagner, Robert, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9775)
      Interview. Wagner was mayor of New York City, 1954-1965. Wagner interview ends at 68 minutes, 16 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with George Dudley until end. Dudley was an architect and gubernatorial aide to Nelson Rockefeller. Dudley worked alongside Wallace Harrison in designing and building the United Nations, Rockefeller Center, Lincoln Center, and the Empire State Plaza in Albany.
    - Walker, Wyatt Tee, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9776)
      Interview. Walker was pastor of the Canaan Baptist Church in Harlem, 1967-2004. In the early 1970s, he was an urban affairs specialist for Governor Nelson Rockefeller. In 1971, he was one of the negotiators who met with leaders of the Attica prison uprising. Before coming to New York, Walker was one of the founders of the Southern Christian Leadership Conference (SCLC). In 1960, he became the executive director of SCLC and Dr. Martin Luther King Jr.'s chief of staff.
    - Wallis, Jim, circa1980s; Sound, 188 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9777)
      Interview. Wallis was Nelson Rockefeller's nephew. Wallis interview ends at 128 minutes, 42 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Louis Levine until 134 minutes, 34 seconds. Levine was New York State Industrial Commissioner, 1966-1976. Tape then contains partial interview with Ogden Reid until 143 minutes, 43 seconds. Reid was appointed to the New York State Commission on Discrimination in 1961 by Governor Nelson Rockefeller. Reid also served six terms in the United States House of Representatives, 1963-1975. He switched from Republican to Democrat in 1972. Tape then contains partial interview with George Dudely until end. Dudley was an architect and gubernatorial aide to Nelson Rockefeller. Dudley worked alongside Wallace Harrison in designing and building the United Nations, Rockefeller Center, Lincoln Center, and the Empire State Plaza in Albany.
    - Wallison, Peter, circa1980s; Sound, 137 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9778)
      Interview. Wallison was special assistant to Nelson Rockefeller, 1971-1976, and counsel to Vice President Rockefeller, 1972-1976.
    - Walsh, John, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9779)
      Interview. Walsh was an assistant attorney general, 1957-1958, and served in Governor Nelson Rockefeller's administrations in various capacities, including as an assistant appointments officer and advance man.
    - Warburg, Edward, 1982 March 30; Sound, 185 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9780)
      Interview. Warburg was a philanthropist and friend of Nelson Rockefeller. He served on the board of trustees at the Museum of Modern Art, 1932-1958, and was a trustee and organizer of the museum's film library. He was also vice director for public affairs of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1971-1974. In addition, Warbur was a co-founder of the American Ballet and the School of American Ballet.
    - Watts, Bill, circa1980s; Sound, 70 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9781)
      Interview. Watts served in the Foreign Service, 1956-1965, as a specialist in Chinese and Soviet affairs. He then served under Governor Nelson Rockefeller in the late 1960s as director of the Office for Urban Innovation. Starting in 1969, Watts was staff secretary of Presdient Richard Nixon's National Security Council for 18 months before resigning to protest planned military operations in Cambodia.
    - Weaver, Sylvester "Pat", circa1980s; Sound, 59 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9782)
      Interview. Weaver was a Dartmouth classmate of and campaign aide to Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Weaver, Warren, circa1980s; Sound, 82 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9783)
      Interview. Weaver was a reporter in the Washington Bureau of the New York Times who covered Nelson Rockefeller for many years as Governor of New York and presidential candidate.
    - Webb, Charles, circa1980s; Sound, 190 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9784)
      Interview. Webb was counsel to New York State Assemblyman Perry Duryea and worked on the reapportionment of legislature districts.
    - Weinstein, Moses, circa1980s; Sound, 70 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9785)
      Interview. Weinstein was a Democratic New York State Assemblyman, 1959-1969, and majority leader, 1965-1968. He became Acting Speaker when Speaker Anthony J. Travia resigned after the close of the legislative session in 1968. He was also chairman of the Queens Democratic Party, 1962-1969. In 1969, Weinstein was elected to the New York State Supreme Court.
    - Wharton, Clifton, circa1980s; Sound, 47 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9786)
      Interview. Wharton worked for the American International Association for Economic and Social Development, 1948-1953. He served as associate, then as director of operations for the American Development Council, 1958-1964. He was a member of the Rockefeller presidential mission to Latin America in 1969. In October 1969, Wharton was elected president of Michigan State University, thereby becoming the first African-American president of a major United States university. In 1978, he became chancellor of the State University of New York system. In 1982, Wharton was named chairman of the Rockefeller Foundation.
    - White, F. Clifton - Part 1, circa1980s; Sound, 47 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9787A)
      Interview. White was a political consultant and campaign manager for Republican Party and New York Conservative Party candidates. He was also a leader of the Draft Goldwater Committee, 1961-1964.
    - White, F. Clifton - Part 2, circa 1980s; Sound, 235 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9787B)
    - Whiteman, Michael, circa1980s; Sound, 95 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9788)
      Interview. Whiteman worked on Governor Nelson Rockfeller's staff in various capacities from 1963 to 1973, including as confidential law assistant and counsel to the governor. He was then counsel to Governor Malcolm Wilson.
    - Whitney, Marylou, 1982 September 17; Sound, 124 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9790)
    - Widmayer, Charles, circa1980s; Sound, 58 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9791)
      Interview. Widmayer was a Dartmouth classmate of Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Wiebe, Richard, circa1980s; Sound, 188 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9792)
      Interview. Wiebe served under Nelson Rockefeller in the New York State Program Office on the program that led to the Pure Waters Act; also on the Adirondacks Park Commission. Wiebe interview ends at 155 minutes, 15 seconds. Tape then contains partial interivew with Joan Braden until end. Braden was a friend of Nelson Rockefeller and a Rockefeller family aide.
    - Wiggin, James, circa1980s; Sound, 47 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9793)
      Interview. Wiggin was a Dartmouth classmate of Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Williams, Nadia, circa1980s; Sound, 279 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9794)
      Interview. Williams was on Nelson Rockefeller's staff at the Office of the Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs and the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare.
    - Wilson, Lois, circa1980s; Sound, 48 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9795)
      Interview. Wilson was a deputy secretary to Governor Nelson Rockefelelr and then special assistant for education to Governors Rockefeller and Hugh Carey. Wilson interview ends at 45 minutes, 16 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Roswell Perkins until end. Perkins was assistant secretary at the Department of Health, Education and Welfare, 1953-1956, and counsel to Governor Nelson Rockefeller, 1958-1959.
    - Wilson, Malcom - Part 1, circa1980s; Sound, 320 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9796)
      Interview. Wilson was a New York State Assemblyman, 1939-1958, Lieutenant Governor of New York, 1959-1973, and Governor of New York, 1973-1974.
    - Wilson, Malcolm - Part 2, circa1980s; Sound, 278 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9797)
      Interview. Wilson was a New York State Assemblyman, 1939-1958, Lieutenant Governor of New York, 1959-1973, and Governor of New York, 1973-1974. Wilson interiview ends at 67 minutes. Tape then contains partial interview with John Lockwood until 93 minutes, 33 seconds. Lockwood was chief legal adviser to the Rockefeller family and chairman of the New York Public Library. Tape then continues with Wilson interview until end.
    - Wodell, Margaret, circa1980s; Sound, 60 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9798)
      Interview. Wodell was a friend of Nelson Rockefeller's family while growing up in Seal Harbor, Maine. Wodell interview ends at 23 minutes, 25 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Bill Sharkey. Sharkey was chief of revenue estimating for the New York State Department of Taxation and Finance. He moved on to work in the governor's office in 1959 where he worked on various tax and budgeting projects under Governor Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Wolfgang, Jerry, circa1980s; Sound, 188 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9799)
      Interview. Wolfgang was an advance man for Governor Nelson Rockefeller's campaigns as well as for Governor Rockefeller's 1969 fact-finding mission to Argentina and the embattled military government of Juan Carlos Ongania.
    - Zimmerman, Donald, circa1980s; Sound, 137 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9800)
      Interview. Zimmmerman was a lawyer in the Appellate Division of the New York State Supreme Court, eventually rising to chief law assistant. He was then a New York State Supreme Court Justice in the Bronx and counsel to the New York State Republican Senate majority leadership. Zimmerman also served as counsel to the Joint Legislative Committee on Reapportionment and worked on the Waterfront Commmission.